superfan.com 2014-03-30

# BranchOut - Leverage Your Professional Network on Facebook

BranchOut, Inc. ("BranchOut") operates the BranchOut services to make professional networking easy, fun, and effective. You can use BranchOut to search for a job, source leads for recruiting or sales, and build your network of professional connections.

We provide this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies regarding the collection, use, disclosure and protection of information. This Privacy Policy applies to all BranchOut professional networking web sites (including BranchOut.com), mobile features, applications, and other interactive features or services that link to this privacy policy ("BranchOut Services"). This privacy policy only covers information collected through the BranchOut Services and does not cover any information collected outside of the BranchOut Services or offline BranchOut (unless specifically stated otherwise). Your use of the BranchOut Services is subject to our [Terms of Service](https://branchout.com/about/terms). 

## SUMMARY

**WE FULLY DESCRIBE OUR PRIVACY PRACTICES BELOW IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. THIS SUMMARY HIGHLIGHTS SOME IMPORTANT INFORMATION REGARDING THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND OUR USE AND SHARING OF YOUR INFORMATION; BUT PLEASE REVIEW OUR FULL PRIVACY POLICY BEFORE USING OUR SITE.**

  * When you log into BranchOut, you agree to give us access to your Facebook profile and similar information in order to create a profile on BranchOut that will be searchable by other BranchOut users. Please note that your BranchOut Profile and your Connections (defined below) will be visible to all other users of BranchOut. Click here for additional information on how BranchOut works.
  * In addition to information we receive from Facebook, we may also collect information from you directly or automatically when you visit the BranchOut Services. Click here for additional information about the information that we collect.
  * We primarily use your information to provide the BranchOut Services and to contact you regarding your use of the BranchOut Services and information that may interest you. For a full description of how we may use information collected through the BranchOut Services, click here.
  * BranchOut does not share your Personal Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. However, we may share information, including Personal Information, in certain limited circumstances. Click here for additional information regarding the information that we may share with others.
  * In connection with serving content and providing analytics and advertising services, third parties may collect certain information about your visits to this or other web sites and we may receive information regarding the use of the BranchOut Services and the effectiveness of our advertisements. These third parties may set and access their own tracking technologies (including cookies and web beacons) and they may otherwise collect or have access to information about you and your online browsing activities. Click here for additional information.

Back to top ↑

## 1\. BRANCHOUT BASICS

Through the BranchOut Services, you have the opportunity for potential employers, business partners, BranchOut customers, professional contacts and friends to find and learn about you based on your existing Facebook profile, which is the basis for your BranchOut profile. We allow our members to learn about business opportunities and jobs and obtain Introductions.

Users may be individual job seekers, recruiters, sales professionals or others looking for professional connections. There are primarily two types of users on BranchOut:

  * **BranchOut User.** A BranchOut User is a user who has registered to join BranchOut by installing any of the BranchOut Services or who has otherwise logged into BranchOut to use the BranchOut Services.
  * **Connections.** Your Connections consist of your connections to (1) other BranchOut Users and (2) persons who are not BranchOut Users, but are connected to you through your Facebook social network (e.g., a Facebook friend or a second-degree Facebook friend). A BranchOut User who searches for a job, a company or organization, or a person on BranchOut will see any Connections he or she has to the applicable company (or organization) or person.
  * **Enterprise Users.** Enterprise Users are BranchOut Users who are recruiters, sales professionals and other customers looking for qualified candidates, business partners, and sales leads. We may charge Enterprise Users a fee for accessing the BranchOut Services and we may offer special services to Enterprise Users. Like all BranchOut Users, Enterprise Users will have access to view your BranchOut Profile and Connections and may contact you through the communication tools provided by Facebook.

Please note that your BranchOut Profile and your Connections will be visible to all other users of BranchOut. You will be able to contact other BranchOut users through their Facebook page and in accordance with their settings on Facebook. Other BranchOut Users will be able to contact you in the same way, also in accordance with your settings through Facebook.

Back to top ↑

## 2\. INFORMATION COLLECTED BY THE BRANCHOUT SERVICES

  1. **Information We Receive From Facebook**

BranchOut believes that your friends and family are your true support network both personally and professionally. Thus, BranchOut allows you to establish a professional network on BranchOut based on your Facebook friends and their network. 

By accessing BranchOut with your Facebook log-in credentials, you are authorizing BranchOut to collect, store, and use, in accordance with this Privacy Policy, any and all information that you agreed that Facebook could provide to BranchOut. You may also grant us additional permissions at other times. Information is provided to us by Facebook under the terms of Facebook's data use policy (or other applicable Facebook policy).

BranchOut will access and store certain information from your current Facebook profile (for example, your first and last name, email address, current city and state, your work history and education, your profile picture, your Facebook user ID number and demographic information, such as your age and gender, as well as other information that you have made public on Facebook), all in accordance with the permissions you have granted BranchOut. We also access your friends' and their friends' names and applicable user ID number, profile photos, work history and education so that you can create and build your professional network.

In order to help you instantly build your professional network, BranchOut will continue to update your network of friends and their friends, but the rest of your BranchOut profile will not change if you change your Facebook profile.

  2. **Information We Collect From You Directly**

In addition to the information we receive from Facebook, when you use the BranchOut Services, we may ask you to provide personally identifiable information, which is information that identifies you as a specific individual ("Personal Information"), and other information about you, such as demographic information (your gender, ZIP code or similar information), registration and payment information (typically, credit card account information), and certain information about your preferences and interests. If we combine demographic, or similar information with the Personal Information we collect, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

The BranchOut Services are not intended for children younger than the age of 13. If we learn that we have inadvertently gathered personal information from children younger than the age of 13, we will take reasonable measures to delete such information from our records.

  3. **Your BranchOut Profile**

Your BranchOut Profile consists of information provided by you or that you have allowed us to access through your Facebook account. Your BranchOut Profile is visible to all BranchOut Users.

  4. **Information Collected Automatically When You Interact**

With The BranchOut Services — Cookies And Similar Technologies.

We and our third party service providers, including third party network advertising companies and content providers, may use a variety of technologies that automatically or passively collect certain information whenever you visit or interact with the BranchOut Services ("Usage Information"). Usage Information may include the browser and operating system you are using, the URL or advertisement that referred you to the BranchOut Services, the search terms you entered into a search engine that lead you to BranchOut (if applicable), and information about your interactions with the BranchOut Services (such as the pages and content you view and actions you take, the time you accessed BranchOut, and the duration of that period of access), among other information.

In addition, Usage Information also includes your IP address or other unique identifier ("Device Identifier") for any computer, mobile phone or other device (any, a "Device") you may use to access the BranchOut Services. A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your Device used to access a web site, and our servers identify your Device by its Device Identifier. If you use the BranchOut Services on a mobile device, we may also receive information about your mobile device, such as your UDID, mobile operating system, the name of your mobile carrier, and your location information (e.g., GPS coordinates or network-based location).

The methods we may use to collect Usage Information include the following:

    * Cookies: A cookie is a data file placed on a Device when it is used to visit the BranchOut Services or otherwise access our online content. Cookies may be used for many purposes, including, without limitation, remembering you and your preferences and tracking your visits to our web pages. A Flash cookie is a data file placed on a Device via the Adobe Flash plugin that may be built-in to or downloaded by you to your Device. Flash cookies may be used for various purposes, including, without limitation, enabling a Flash feature and remembering your preferences. For more information about Flash and the privacy choices Adobe offers, visit this site. If you choose to disable cookies or to adjust your Flash privacy settings on your Device, some features of the BranchOut Site may not function properly.
    * Web Beacons: A web beacon is a small (often invisible) graphic image or other web programming code embedded in a web page or email. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to the BranchOut Services, to monitor how users navigate the BranchOut Services and to count how many e-mails that were sent were actually opened.
    * Embedded Scripts. An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Service, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your Device from our server or a third party service provider and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

In addition, we may use a variety of other technologies that collect similar information for security and fraud detection purposes. 

  5. **Information We Receive From Third Parties**

We may receive information about you from third parties. For example, if you are on another web site or are using another app and you agree to receive information from BranchOut, that web site or app will forward your contact and other information to us so that we may contact you as requested.

BranchOut may offer you the ability to import your professional information from your resume or through third party services so that you can display such information in your BranchOut Profile. Any information that you choose to import will become part of your BranchOut Profile. BranchOut may also offer the ability to help you import your contacts to the BranchOut Services, for instance, by asking for your login information for your email account. If you choose to import contacts, BranchOut will store those contacts for purposes of helping you and your contacts make connections on BranchOut. BranchOut will not store the passwords you provided without your consent.

As noted above, once you choose to log-in with your Facebook credentials, BranchOut receives certain information from Facebook when you use the BranchOut Services. In addition, we may receive information about you if other users of Facebook give us access to their profiles and you are one of their "connections" or information about you is otherwise accessible through Facebook, or similar page on a social networking or other third party web site or interactive service.

We also may supplement the information we collect with outside records from third parties in order to provide you with information, services or goods you have requested. We may combine the information we receive from those other sources with information we collect through the BranchOut Services. In those cases, we will apply this Privacy Policy to the combined information.

Back to top ↑

## 3\. HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

We may use your information as disclosed to you at the time you provide it or choose to participate in a feature or otherwise with your consent. In addition, BranchOut uses information about you, including Personal Information and Usage Information, to register you for, and enable you to use, the BranchOut Services; to help serve you relevant and meaningful content; to improve the BranchOut Services and for our internal business purposes; to contact you regarding the BranchOut Services (e.g., to respond to your customer support inquiries, to update you regarding the activity of your Connections, to provide you with professional opportunities); and to send you promotional messages on our behalf or on behalf of our partners.

Back to top ↑

## 4\. HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION

We do not share your Personal Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. We may share your information (which may include Personal Information and Usage Information) with third parties (not BranchOut) with your consent, as disclosed in this privacy policy or at the time you provide us with information, and in the following circumstances:

Third Party Service Providers. We may provide information to service providers that help us bring you the services we offer. For example, we may use third parties to help host the BranchOut Site, send out email updates about BranchOut, remove repetitive information from our user lists, process payments, or provide search results or links (including sponsored links). If you purchase any products or services from BranchOut, our billing partner will receive billing and financial information (e.g., credit card numbers) necessary to process your charges, including your postal and e-mail addresses, depending on your payment method.

Legal Requests, Investigations and Safety. We may transfer and disclose information, including Personal Information and Usage Information, to third parties to comply with a legal obligation; when we believe in good faith that the law requires it; at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; to verify or enforce our Terms of Services or other applicable policies; to respond to an emergency; or otherwise to protect the rights, property, safety, or security of third parties, users of the BranchOut Services or the public. We may also use Device Identifiers to identify users, and may do so in cooperation with copyright owners, Internet service providers, wireless service providers or law enforcement agencies, in our discretion.

Business Transfers. We may share information, including Personal Information, with our parents, subsidiaries, and affiliates, primarily for business and operational purposes. BranchOut reserves the right to disclose and transfer user information, including Personal Information, in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of certain stock and/or assets, or other corporate change including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process.

Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions. We may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions (each, a "Promotion") that may require registration. If you choose to participate in a Promotion, your Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties in connection with the administration of such Promotion, such as in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, and as required by law, such as on a winners list. By entering a Promotion, you are agreeing to the official rules that govern that Promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor and/or other parties to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing materials.

Non-Personal Information. We may share non-personal information, such as aggregated user statistics, with third parties for a variety of purposes, but we only do so in such a way that no individual user is specifically identified or specifically linked to any action or information.

Back to top ↑

## 5\. ANALYTICS, ADVERTISING, AND SIMILAR THIRD PARTIES

Although the BranchOut Service currently does not display ads from third parties, BranchOut works with network advertisers, ad agencies, third party traffic measurement services and other vendors to provide us with information regarding traffic through the BranchOut Services, to serve our advertisements on other web sites, within third party applications, and across the Internet, and to provide us with information regarding the use of the BranchOut Services and the effectiveness of our advertisements. In connection with providing analytics and advertisement services, our service providers may collect certain information about your visits to this or other Services. Some of these parties may collect Personal Information when you use the BranchOut Services or other web sites or services. These service providers may also set and access their own tracking technologies on your computer or device (including cookies and web beacons) and may otherwise collect or have access to information about you (such as your general interest in career networking and Usage Information). Cookies and web beacons, including those set by third party network advertisers, may be used to, among other things, target advertisements, prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times and to conduct research regarding the usefulness of certain advertisements to you. We may share Usage Information about visitors with third party advertising companies, analytics providers and other vendors for similar purposes.

While we may use a variety of service providers to perform advertising services for us, some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI") or the Digital Advertising Alliance ("DAA") Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. You may want to visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp, which provides information regarding targeted advertising and the "opt-out" procedures of NAI members. You may also want to visit or http://www.aboutads.info/choices/, which provides information regarding targeted advertising and offers an "opt-out" by participating companies in the DAA Self-Regulatory Program. Please note that these opt-out mechanisms are not opt-outs from all online advertising.  Even if you opt-out, you will continue to see generic ads online.

Back to top ↑

## 6\. HOW TO ACCESS AND UPDATE YOUR INFORMATION

Information We Receive From Facebook. To manage the information BranchOut receives about you from Facebook, you will need to follow the instructions in your "Account" and "Privacy Settings" on Facebook (or similar features as determined by Facebook) for updating your information and changing your privacy settings. Once BranchOut receives your information from Facebook, that information is stored and used by BranchOut in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Closing Your Account. We would hate to see you go, but if you no longer want BranchOut to make active use of your information, you may send an e-mail to contact@branchout.com. Place "Delete My Account" in the subject line and include your first name, last name, e-mail address used to log in to BranchOut in the body of the e-mail. We may also offer an online feature that allows you to disable or close your account. Please note that some information may not be able to be deleted from all databases and backup records and that certain records, for example those pertaining to payments or customer service matters, will be retained for legal and accounting purposes. Also, if you have posted content on or through the BranchOut Services, we may not be able to delete it.

Back to top ↑

## 7\. CHANGING YOUR PREFERENCES AND SUBSCRIPTIONS

The BranchOut Service may contain web pages or other features through which you may be able to unsubscribe or modify the e-mail newsletters or similar communications we send to you. Also, users who receive a newsletter or other similar e-mails from us and who wish to remove themselves from the mailing list (i.e. opt out) can do so by following the link provided in an e-mail received. However, please note that we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to your account or use of the BranchOut Services (for example, administrative and service announcements) and these transactional account messages may be unaffected if you opt-out from receiving promotional messages.

Back to top ↑

## 8\. SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION

We take commercially reasonable steps to protect and secure your Personal Information. However, no data transmission over the Internet or wireless networks or electronic storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Please note that we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information we collect. You use our Service and provide us with your information at your own risk.

Back to top ↑

## 9\. LINKS TO THIRD PARTIES AND BRANCHOUT CONTENT FOUND OUTSIDE THE BRANCHOUT SERVICES

When you are using the BranchOut Services, you may be directed to other web sites or online services that are operated and controlled by third parties that are beyond our control. In addition, BranchOut content and widgets may be included on web pages and web sites that are not associated with us and over which we have no control. These third parties may independently collect data. BranchOut is not responsible for the privacy practices of any third party.

Back to top ↑

## 10\. CONSENT TO TRANSFER

The BranchOut Services are operated in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect will be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using the BranchOut Services, or providing us with any information, you fully understand and unambiguously consent to this transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States, a jurisdiction in which the privacy laws may not be as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside and/or are a citizen.

Back to top ↑

## 11\. CHANGES

BranchOut may update this policy from time to time and any changes will be effective upon posting. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your BranchOut account or by placing a prominent notice on the BranchOut Site. However, we will use your personal information in a manner consistent with the Privacy Policy in effect at the time you submitted the information, unless you consent to the new or revised policy.

Back to top ↑

## 12\. CONTACT US

If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding our Privacy Policy and/or practices, please send an e-mail to [privacy@branchout.com](mailto:privacy@branchout.com). Any other questions or inquiries should be directed to BranchOut Customer Care at [contact@branchout.com](mailto:contact@branchout.com).

Back to top ↑
